<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open positions | Lloréns-Rico Lab</title>
    <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://llorensricolab.com/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Open positions</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://llorensricolab.com/media/icon_hua5ea9da2a87aac581422e10945bb0806_3794_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Open positions</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for expressions of interest, MSCA postdoctoral fellowships</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/postdoc_msca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/join/postdoc_msca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Systems Biology of Host-Microbiome Interactions&lt;/strong&gt; group is looking to recruit a postdoc through the international MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships call. Different research areas are available in the context of national or european projects, both in wet- and dry-lab. We are looking for postdocs with a genuine interest in understanding microbial functions in the context of the gut microbiome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The postdoc will be hosted at the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centro de Investigación Príncipe Felipe (CIPF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in Valencia, Spain, a leading biomedical institute developing competitive and internationally relevant research in the fields of metabolic disorders, cancer and neuronal pathologies. The research centre, located in Valencia, occupies an area of 32,000m2 and it is equipped with the most advanced infraestructures, facilities and technological equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibilities and qualifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dry lab postdocs: We are looking for a candidate with a PhD in bioinformatics, computational biology or related disciplines, with experience in analyses of metagenomics data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wet lab postdocs: We are looking for a candidate with a PhD in microbiology, molecular biology or related disciplines, with experience in molecular microbiology and/or microbiome experiments using animal models (mouse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, we have the possibility of providing a postdoctoral contract (up to 1 year), so selected candidates may be able to join before the call results are announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to apply:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested candidates should send their CV, cover letter and contact details for two references to the following email address: vllorens (at) cipf (dot) es before June 20th, 2024. The CV should remove all personal references to gender, age, marital status, nationality and should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; include a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
