<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open positions | Lloréns-Rico Lab</title>
    <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://llorensricolab.com/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Open positions</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://llorensricolab.com/media/icon_hua5ea9da2a87aac581422e10945bb0806_3794_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Open positions</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral researcher on bacterial genome editing</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/join/postdoc_crispr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/join/postdoc_crispr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Systems Biology of Host-Microbiome Interactions&lt;/strong&gt; group is looking to recruit a postdoc in bacterial genome editing to work in the context of the ERC project REGUBIOME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Project REGUBIOME aims to understand the role of transcriptional regulation in the gut microbiota, and the impact of the regulation of bacterial functions in human health. This project will specifically focus on two bacteria of high relevance for host health: Fusobacterium nucleatum (associated to colorectal cancer) and Lacticaseibacillus rhamnosus (used as a probiotic). In this project we will develop novel high throughput techniques to reconstruct the gene regulatory networks of these bacteria, and we will study the effect of different stimuli on the expression of functions that are relevant for human health. The selected candidate will join the Systems Biology of Host Microbiota Interactions lab, and their functions will entail the design and the implementation of genetic modification tools (CRISPR, CRISPRi) in the two studied bacteria. They will also develop large-scale screening strategies, by designing gRNA libraries against genomic targets and implementing the CRISPR screenings to evaluate the effect of the mutations and modifications introduced in the genomes of these bacteria. Additionally, the selected candidate joining the group will participate in the supervision of students and predoctoral researchers, project management and result dissemination in scientific articles and conferences, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The postdoc will be hosted at the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centro de Investigación Príncipe Felipe (CIPF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in Valencia, Spain, a leading biomedical institute developing competitive and internationally relevant research in the fields of metabolic disorders, cancer and neuronal pathologies. The research centre, located in Valencia, occupies an area of 32,000m2 and it is equipped with the most advanced infraestructures, facilities and technological equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibilities and qualifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Required degree: the candidate must hold a doctorate in Microbiology, Molecular
Biology or any related discipline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent English written and oral skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in bacterial genome editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in CRISPR/CRISPRi genome-wide assays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong knowledge of (gut) bacterial physiology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great organization skills and capability to work as part of a team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though it is not mandatory, we will value prior experience in anaerobic microbiology and in the bioinformatic analysis of the data generated in CRISPR screenings, as well as experience with animal models (mice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer conditions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional category: Postdoctoral researcher R2.II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salary Level: approx 31.000€ gross salary/year (Salary level as stipulated in the Convenio de Sanidad Privada de la Provincia de Valencia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working hours: full-time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration: 2.5 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting date: as soon as possible, expected 1st of May 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to apply:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested candidates should send a full application through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cipf.fundanetsuite.com/ConvocatoriasPropias/es/Convocatorias/VerConvocatoria?Id=98&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official portal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;: The CV should remove all personal references to gender, age, marital status and nationality, and should NOT include a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
