<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Lloréns-Rico Lab</title>
    <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://llorensricolab.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://llorensricolab.com/media/icon_hua5ea9da2a87aac581422e10945bb0806_3794_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Fran!</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-06-2025_fran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-06-2025_fran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fran has recently joined the group as bioinformatician and data analyst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fran Merino has recently joined the lab as bioinformatician and data analyst. With a bachelor in Computer Engineering and a PhD in Biomedical Engineering, he has a strong background in pipeline development and optimization, predictive modeling and big data analysis. He will contribute to different ongoing projects in the lab by performing metagenomic/metatranscriptomic data analysis and developing new pipelines and software tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researchers go to school</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/28-05-2025_rgts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/28-05-2025_rgts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verónica participated in this year&amp;rsquo;s edition of &amp;ldquo;Researchers go to school&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers go to school is an initiative that brings together students from all ages and researchers in various disciplines. Through this action, researchers visit schools to share their knowledge, experiences and passion. Verónica participated in the last edition of this initiative, visiting a public primary school in Valencia. Through a short talk and a card-collecting game, she explained students (aged 8 to 10 years old) the importance of keeping a diverse microbiota with many good bacteria. In total, more than 150 students participated in this activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/28-05-2025_rgts/images/rgts3_hu447e204f4d18572619e9ad6f34ad1dde_236180_e1d2d9581ddc9c9e23b8cca20f520e8e.webp 400w,
               /post/28-05-2025_rgts/images/rgts3_hu447e204f4d18572619e9ad6f34ad1dde_236180_044212e1791db4d1b0d6299dc33d927a.webp 760w,
               /post/28-05-2025_rgts/images/rgts3_hu447e204f4d18572619e9ad6f34ad1dde_236180_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/post/28-05-2025_rgts/images/rgts3_hu447e204f4d18572619e9ad6f34ad1dde_236180_e1d2d9581ddc9c9e23b8cca20f520e8e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Researchers go to school&amp;rdquo; is organized by EsCiencia and the Fundación La Caixa, funded by the EU through a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Action (101162311/HORIZON-MSCA-2023-CITIZENS-01: Marie Sklodowska-Curie-European Night of Researchers and actions of Researchers in Schools 2024-2025).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General meeting of the MIdAS network</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/22-05-2025_midas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/22-05-2025_midas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our PI, Verónica Lloréns-Rico, attended the General Meeting of the Red MIdAS network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lab, which joined this network last year, was represented at the general meeting of the network, which took place on May 22nd at the IMDEA Alimentación research institute in Madrid. The goal of this meeting was to present the results of the different working groups part of the network and to stimulate discussions on how to standardize and improve methodologies in the study of the microbiota, from collection and preservation methods to the bioinformatics analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, an Open Science activity was organized, which included a broad perspective on the human microbiota and a tutorial on web tools to access and analyze microbiome datasets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lab joins the COST Action INFOGUT</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-05-2025_cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-05-2025_cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The network is aimed at standardizing and expanding the use of &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; models of the colon to simulate the intestinal microbiota&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group has recently joined the COST Action INFOGUT (CA23110), formed by researchers across all Europe. This network brings together experts in gastroenterology, biotechnology, bioengineering, physiology, nutrition, biochemistry, bioinformatics, microbiology, etc., with the goal of filling the knowledge gap on &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; colon models and expanding their use in research and regulatory use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab aims to contribute in the following working groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WG1. Review of existing &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; human colon models and harmonized guidelines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WG2. Extension to other gut compartments and host interactions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WG3. Extension to diseased situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab is open to host visitors on short-term scientific missions wishing to learn the techniques for high-throughput culturing we are developing. If you are interested, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/contact/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info on this COST Action can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cost.eu/actions/CA23110/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Raquel!</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-03-2025_raquel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-03-2025_raquel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raquel has joined the lab as an undergraduate student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raquel is a 4th year student of the Degree in Biotechnology at the &lt;em&gt;Universitat Politècnica de València&lt;/em&gt;. She will develop her undergraduate project within our lab, studying the association between human intestinal spirochetosis and irritable bowel syndrome and using a combination of wet- and dry-lab work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11F2025</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/11-02-2025_11f2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/11-02-2025_11f2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lab members participate in the activities to celebrate the 11th of February, the International day of Women and Girls in Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, the lab has participated in different activities to commemorate the 11th of February, the International Day of Women and Girls in Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana Rosa visited the Sant Pasqual primary school in Torrent (Valencia), to give an inspiring talk on her work with gut bacteria in the REGUBIOME project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verónica also participated, visiting the IES Comarcal in Burjassot (Valencia), and giving a talk to high school students on her career, her trajectory and on what are the challenges of being a woman leading a research lab in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Ignacio Lopez Palau receives the best MSc Thesis in Bioinformatics award</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/25-10-2024_premiojesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/25-10-2024_premiojesus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesús defended his MSc thesis in July, and has now received the award at the graduation ceremony of his class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesús did his MSc thesis in our group, starting in November 2023 and finishing in June 2024. He worked on benchmarking a variety of computational tools used for analysis of metatranscriptomes,. His MSc thesis is titled &amp;ldquo;A Comparative Study of Metatranscriptomic Pipelines in Simulated Gut Microbiota Samples&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now he has received an award for the best MSc thesis of his class, promoted by ADM and Biopolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations Jesús!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Researchers Night</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/27-09-2024_ern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/27-09-2024_ern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The team participated in this year&amp;rsquo;s European Researchers Night presenting our REGUBIOME project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the &amp;ldquo;European Researchers&amp;rsquo; Night&amp;rdquo; celebration, our group introduced visitors to our REGUBIOME project. Both children and adults learned about the bacteria that are part of our gut microbiota in particular &lt;em&gt;L. rhamnosus&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt;, and how our habits can change their behavior. It was incredibly satisfying to see the interest shown by the families and friends who attended the event. They had the opportunity to observe bacterial growth plates and the entire microencapsulation process through the microscope. We believe these events are essential for sharing knowledge not only with the scientific community but also with the general public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manuel and Jesus successfully defended their MSc Theses</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/24-09-2024_tfms24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/24-09-2024_tfms24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manuel and Jesús passed their defenses swiftly, congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesús Ignacio López Palau and Manuel José Sánchez Rumí, our two MSc students for the academic year 2023-2024, both defended their theses recently, in July and September, obtaining excellent results! Jesús is now MSc in Bioinformatics (UV) and Manuel obtained his MSc in Biomedical Biotechnology (UPV). Congrats to both of them, and best of luck in your future endeavors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/jesus_hub7faf32e4d18d7fe199f001f342c9871_553102_491548258f7dd20664e2687472f1442b.webp 400w,
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/jesus_hub7faf32e4d18d7fe199f001f342c9871_553102_403c286f98ec5c73c4e2bf78e85e16d3.webp 760w,
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/jesus_hub7faf32e4d18d7fe199f001f342c9871_553102_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/post/24-09-2024_tfms24/jesus_hub7faf32e4d18d7fe199f001f342c9871_553102_491548258f7dd20664e2687472f1442b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/manu_huda42d2e1ac4e0d09f1a5f98d4ea059cb_180466_fbf6903f344a95acced65951ecc7a703.webp 400w,
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/manu_huda42d2e1ac4e0d09f1a5f98d4ea059cb_180466_ff2992abd21df19c0676ac1ab7940736.webp 760w,
               /post/24-09-2024_tfms24/manu_huda42d2e1ac4e0d09f1a5f98d4ea059cb_180466_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/post/24-09-2024_tfms24/manu_huda42d2e1ac4e0d09f1a5f98d4ea059cb_180466_fbf6903f344a95acced65951ecc7a703.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;574&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First lab lunch!</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/14-06-2024_lablunch24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/14-06-2024_lablunch24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I-79 Lab lunch 2024!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 14th we celebrated our first official lab lunch, enjoying a delicious *arròs negre.* The lab is now one and a half years old and we keep growing and learning as a team. Cheers to many more lab traditions to come!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at FISABIO</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/14-05-2024_fisabio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/14-05-2024_fisabio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group leader, Verónica Lloréns-Rico, gave an invited talk at the FISABIO Institute in Valencia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She presented the different projects being currently performed in the Systems Biology of Host-Microbiome Interactions lab at the CIPF. Thanks a lot for the invitation, especially to Prof. Carles Úbeda for hosting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ana Rosa Marquez gets a Best Oral Presentation Award at the VIII Trobada d&#39;Investigadors en Càncer Ciutat d&#39;Alcoi</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Ana Rosa!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana Rosa Márquez obtained one of the best oral presentation awards at the VIII Trobada d&amp;rsquo;Investigadors en Càncer Ciutat d&amp;rsquo;Alcoi, where she presented her preliminary results on the REGUBIOME project. Oral presentation awards were given to the best presentations in each of the areas covered in the meeting, including Microbiota and Cancer, where she got her award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info on the event can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trailsolidarialcoi.org/trobada-2024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lab takes part in the VIII Trobada d&#39;Investigadors en Càncer Ciutat d&#39;Alcoi</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verónica Lloréns-Rico and Ana Rosa Márquez Blesa attended this meeting in Alcoi, where they presented part of the REGUBIOME work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lab has participated in the latest edition of the Trobada d&amp;rsquo;Investigadors en Càncer Ciutat d&amp;rsquo;Alcoi, a scientific meeting that brings together researchers in cancer, studying all aspects of this disease, from the bench to the bedside. Our group leader, Verónica Lloréns Rico, participated in the round table &amp;ldquo;Microbiota y cáncer&amp;rdquo;, where she gave an overview of how the REGUBIOME project aims at understanding the role of the bacterium &lt;em&gt;Fusobacterium nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; in the development of colorectal cancer. Then, our PhD student Ana Rosa Márquez Blesa presented the experimental platform being developed to characterize the gene regulatory networks in &lt;em&gt;Fusobacterium&lt;/em&gt; and other bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Ana Rosa presenting her work&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/ana1_hu8014edee918659033566f393ca364193_776799_0803aaf3ed06484f8feaad4951434fb5.webp 400w,
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/ana1_hu8014edee918659033566f393ca364193_776799_fe46b900df67237fe8020a8cfdedc0c4.webp 760w,
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/ana1_hu8014edee918659033566f393ca364193_776799_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi/ana1_hu8014edee918659033566f393ca364193_776799_0803aaf3ed06484f8feaad4951434fb5.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Verónica presenting&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/vero1_hu9bba283970bcc50d91cd36e5fab286c4_391939_7a7542d8a601904df37387beedbc9e58.webp 400w,
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/vero1_hu9bba283970bcc50d91cd36e5fab286c4_391939_08b649356c1d5a1b461ef6a774678878.webp 760w,
               /post/19-04-2024_alcoi/vero1_hu9bba283970bcc50d91cd36e5fab286c4_391939_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-04-2024_alcoi/vero1_hu9bba283970bcc50d91cd36e5fab286c4_391939_7a7542d8a601904df37387beedbc9e58.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info on the event can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trailsolidarialcoi.org/trobada-2024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veronica Llorens, finalist of the Talento Joven awards</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/28-02-2024_tjcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/28-02-2024_tjcv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Veronica Llorens, our group leader, was selected as finalist of the Talento Joven - Comunitat Valenciana awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was selected as finalist in the science category, in recognition to her international career and her work on the gut microbiota. On February 28th, she attended the award ceremony organized by Levante EMV and LaCaixa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, she was not the winner of the category, but being a finalist is already a big accomplishment. Congrats Verónica!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the finalists &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.levante-emv.com/comunitat-valenciana/2024/02/12/premios-talento-joven-finalistas-ciencia-98092312.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and about the award ceremony and the winners of each category &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.levante-emv.com/comunitat-valenciana/2024/02/28/premios-talento-joven-comunitat-valenciana-2024-98781523.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Ana Rosa!</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-02-2024_anarosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/01-02-2024_anarosa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want to welcome to our group our new PhD student, Ana Rosa Márquez Blesa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana Rosa has joined the lab to work on our ERC-StG REGUBIOME project as a predoctoral researcher. She holds a bachelor in Biotechnology and a MSc in Molecular Biology Applied to Biotechnology Companies. She surely will be a great addition to our team. Welcome Ana Rosa!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at IATA</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-01-2024_iata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/19-01-2024_iata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group leader, Verónica Lloréns-Rico, gave an invited talk at the &lt;em&gt;Instituto de Agroquímica y Tecnología de los Alimentos&lt;/em&gt; (IATA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She presented the different projects being currently performed at the Systems Biology of Host-Microbiome Interactions lab. Thanks a lot for the invitation, especially to Prof. Maria Carmen Collado for hosting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verónica Lloréns presents REGUBIOME at the outreach event &#34;Una horchata por la salud&#34;</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/02-10-2023_horchata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/02-10-2023_horchata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verónica Lloréns presented the ERC StG project REGUBIOME to the general public in an outreach event organized by FECYT in the context of the Spanish presidency of the Council of the European Union and the conference on Personalized Medicine that is taking place in Valencia these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organizers of the event &amp;ldquo;Una horchata por la ciencia&amp;rdquo; invited local researchers working on EU-funded projects, to bring excellent science being done in Valencia closer to the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lloréns-Rico Lab receives an ERC StG 2023</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/23-09-05_erc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/23-09-05_erc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project REGUBIOME has received one of the highly competitive ERC Starting grants, receiving 1.5M€ to pursue research on gene regulation in gut bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to press release: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cipf.es/archives/39240&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.cipf.es/archives/39240&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to article in Levante: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.levante-emv.com/comunitat-valenciana/2023/09/05/joven-valenciana-veronica-llorens-rico-91727959.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.levante-emv.com/comunitat-valenciana/2023/09/05/joven-valenciana-veronica-llorens-rico-91727959.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to interview in Valencia Plaza: &lt;a href=&#34;https://valenciaplaza.com/veronica-llorens-investigacion-abrir-puertas-medicina-personalizada&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://valenciaplaza.com/veronica-llorens-investigacion-abrir-puertas-medicina-personalizada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lloréns-Rico group has received funding from the Agencia Estatal de Innovación</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/23-07-17_pgc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/23-07-17_pgc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project has been awarded a &lt;em&gt;Proyectos de Generación de Conocimiento 2022&lt;/em&gt; grant to study transcriptional variation in the gut microbiome during the next three years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at CABD</title>
      <link>https://llorensricolab.com/post/22-11-25_talk_cabd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://llorensricolab.com/post/22-11-25_talk_cabd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group leader, Verónica Lloréns-Rico, gave an invited talk at the &lt;em&gt;Centro Andaluz de Biología del Desarrollo&lt;/em&gt; (CABD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She presented her previous work, as well as her vision for her newly established lab. The day was completed with plenty of discussions with the different groups at the CABD. Thanks a lot for the invitation, especially to Prof. Peter Askjaer for hosting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
